Contact

7208549087 (Mobile) ericatindall@icloud.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ericatindall-589a9032 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Inpatient

Critical Care

Cardiac Surgery

Certifications

Registered Nurse

Registered Nurse

Registered Nurse

Critical Care Registered Nurse (Adult) (CCRN-A)

Erica Tindall

RN, CCRN

Greater Seattle Area

Summary

28 years of Registered Nursing experience both here in the USA and Australia, where I obtained my initial Registered Nurse education.

16 years of Critical Care practice including Cardio-Thoracic surgery, Neurology, Neurosurgery, Cardiology, Pulmonary, Trauma, and general Medical-Surgical in a variety of academic and community critical care units.

Current WA State RN Licensure.

CCRN credential obtained in 2016.

Critical Care Residency 2002.

Current ACLS / BLS / NIHSS certification.

Passionate about nursing and providing exceptional patient care.

Advanced clinical assessment and critical care experience inclusive of -

Complex hemodynamic monitoring (CCO; mixed and central venous oximetry; LAP monitoring)

Mechanical ventilation protocols and EtCO2 monitoring.

Cardiothoracic surgery recovery.

Thoracic and epicardial drainage.

Cardiac pacing

Intra Aortic Balloon Counterpulsation therapy

Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy

pre/post endovascular cardiology and neurology; arterial and venous sheath management.

ICP monitoring

Postanesthesia recovery and procedural moderate sedation.

EMR documentation (EPIC/Cerner) with integrated bar-coded medication administration.

Experience

EvergreenHealth
Registered Nurse
November 2019 - Present (8 months)

Kirkland, Washington

Critical Care Unit

Mechanical ventilation

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

pre/post EP Lab and Interventional Cardiology

pre/post-Endovascular Neurology

ICP monitoring

Level III Trauma service

CHI Franciscan Health

1 year 10 months

Registered Nurse

June 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Burien WA

Regional Hospital for Respiratory and Complex Care

Extended Critical Care

Mechanical Ventilator weaning

Care of medically complex patients

Registered Nurse

February 2018 - May 2018 (4 months)

Bremerton, Washington, United States

Harrison Medical Center

Postanesthesia Care Unit/PreOP

Phase I and Phase II care

MultiCare Health System

3 years 5 months

Registered Nurse

September 2017 - February 2018 (6 months)

Tacoma, Washington

Tacoma General Hospital

GI Special Procedures

Pain Management Services

Moderate Sedation

Postanesthesia Care

Registered Nurse

June 2016 - September 2017 (1 year 4 months)

Tacoma, Washington, United States

Tacoma General Hospital, Mary Bridge Children's Hospital, Baker Day Surgery

Perioperative Services

AORN Perioperative 101 Residency

Registered Nurse

October 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Tacoma, Washington, United States

Tacoma General Hospital

Medical-Surgical / Neuroscience Intensive Care Unit

CCRN Credential obtained

Mechanical ventilation

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

pre/post EP Lab and Interventional Cardiology

ICP monitoring

Level II Trauma service

CHI Franciscan Health

Registered Nurse

September 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Tacoma, Washington, United States

St Joseph Medical Center

Cardiac Surgery Intensive Care Unit

Cardiothoracic surgery recovery

Randstad Healthcare

Registered Nurse

May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months)

San Jose, California, United States

Good Samaritan Hospital

Medical-Surgical ICU / Cardiovascular ICU Travel contract

Seattle Children's

Registered Nurse

November 2012 - March 2013 (5 months)

Seattle, Washington, United States

Cardiac Intensive Care Unit

Pediatric Cardiac Critical Care residency

Community Hospital of the Monterey Peninsula

Registered Nurse

February 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 9 months)

Monterey, California, United States

Intensive Care Unit

Mechanical ventilation

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

pre/post EP Lab and Interventional Cardiology

ICP monitoring

Boulder Community Health

Registered Nurse

November 2007 - February 2011 (3 years 4 months)

Boulder, Colorado, United States

Critical Care Unit

Cardiovascular surgery recovery

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

IABP

CRRT

Level II Trauma

Sentara Healthcare

Registered Nurse

September 2006 - November 2007 (1 year 3 months)

Norfolk, Virginia, United States

Sentara Heart Hospital

Cardiac Surgery Intensive Care Unit

Cardiovascular surgery recovery

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

IABP

CRRT

Kadlec Medical Center

Registered Nurse

July 2002 - August 2006 (4 years 2 months)

Richland, Washington, United States

Intensive Care Unit

ICU Residency

Level III Trauma service

Complex hemodynamic monitoring

Management of vasoactive infusions

Cardiovascular surgery recovery

IABP

CRRT

pre/post EP Lab and Interventional Cardiology

Various Acute Care travel nursing Registered Nurse 1993 - 2002 (9 years)

USA, Nationwide

Various acute care travel nursing contracts with multiple companies in a variety of academic and community medical centers throughout the USA.

Clinical practice areas inclusive of

Geriatric-Psychiatry

Medical-Surgical

Long Term Acute Care - medically complex patients

Postanesthesia Care Unit

Neurology and Neuro Progressive Care (Cardiac telemetry and continuous

EEG monitoring)

Orthopedic

Trauma

GYN-oncology

Oncology and Bone Marrow Transplant

Education

Box Hill Hospital School of Nursing, Melbourne Australia Certificate of Registered General Nursing, Nursing (1987 - 1991)